Hey, y'all. Head on over to Amanda Land Exports. I just dropped a new drop.
Support, support, support. Let's talk about emotional intelligence. Now, I want y'all to
be really, really honest with yourselves. If a friend comes to you and says, oh, hold on,
let me block this person. I really don't know who the fuck y'all be thinking you're talking to.
So if a friend, oh, actually, so here's the notebook, the Amanda Land, Views for Amanda Land
notebook. The bookmarks are coming in tomorrow, but here is the Views for Amanda Land pin.
And here is the Views for Amanda Land Word of the Day logbook. It comes with words of resistance
in the first page. And this gives you the opportunity to keep track of your words of
the day. You know, Views for Amanda Land is my show that I created after I was fired from
Radio 1 for being too polarizing and not consistently funny. And so I'm really proud of it because
it is completely homegrown from the joy of learning and teaching. Every time I'm teaching y'all,
I am learning. I am learning as well. Is this for a teen boy? I don't see why not.
And so the books have this circle so that you can number them so that you can keep,
you know, keep up. So this is the first, you know, so you will put a one here so that when
you fill this up, right, when you fill it up, then you can get the next one. And since
the show is once a week, you know, you're going to, it's going to take you a while to
fill it up. And then at the back, it has a doodle page. For all my doodlers. So, you
know, these are the stuff that I'm just creating. It's not, it's not super fancy. You know, it's
it's definitely not, um, it's, it's quality, but that's just because like, I've been really
fortunate to work with folks that really care about the work that they do. And, um, and I'm
really thoughtful about trying to make stuff that people, um, that's not just for consumerism
purposes, right? Like it has a use. It has a use. So also the sticker tabs are coming.
They haven't come yet, but this comes with sticker tabs. And so the sticker tabs are going to be
so that you can put tabs so that you can flip to the different sections. Because when we do the
show of views from Amanda land, like we have different sections of the show, right? So we have
the, the, uh, critical thinking segment. We have the 60 seconds headline segment. We have level us up.
And so I know if you're like me, you want to take, if you're like me, you want to be organized and
taking your notes. So you're going to want to put the tab right here so that you can open to
critical thinking. And then you can put your tab for the other section here, et cetera.
So, um, really just excited to never do shirts again. Cause I hate sending shirts. Yes. It's
spiral. So you guys like a spiral bound notebook. You prefer spiral. Interesting. Cause I wasn't sure
how people feel about a spiral, a spiral bound notebook. Um, but I really want like, this is,
this is where I want to go with my work. I want to make paper goods. I want to make notebooks and
cards. And I want to make things that are tangible, like that are outside of the digital space,
you know, things that you, like, I still keep postcards and letters and greeting cards and all
of my notebooks. Like I keep all of that stuff because I think it's, I like touching it. I like
the tech, the tactile, right? So y'all like spirals. That's really good news. That's really good news
because my printer who I really like, he was like, that's what we do. We do the spirals. Um,
and just a side note before I get into the main conversation around emotional maturity. Um,
I, I had went to another printer around my way and I asked them about putting, um,
putting like lined paper in the, um, notebook and they sent me a message and said,
we don't have lined paper just lying around. So what, um, so can you design some and send to us?
And I just didn't like that tone. So I was like, you're going to have to find, you have to be patient.
And for some of us, it's really hard to do that. We'll be like, thank you, Harvey. We'll be like,
dang, this is the only option. No, I'm trying to tell y'all if you can explore,
explore other options because the printer I found,
listen, he, when I showed up today, he was like, I Googled you this weekend.
I watched a comedy special, funny stuff, funny stuff. And by the way, when I said to him,
um, how would you put the lined, the lined notebooks at the lined paper in the notebooks? He was like,
I would design lined paper. Okay. I'm taking notes, nude, nude paper,
nude brown color sheets. Okay. So let's talk about, um, let's talk about emotional maturity
because I want you to be really honest with yourself. Take, take, just take a moment.
And I want you to ask yourself when a friend or a family member comes to you with a complaint
about your behavior or with an expression of how, how they felt in response to something you said to
them. What is your first instinct? Be honest. What's your first instinct? I'm saying this because
I love you for being honest, Lazuli Pearl, that eighties kidnap. Thank you all so much for being
honest. Cause we're going to get through that. We're going to work through this right now.
This is in the way this is in the way. And of course, some people are repeat offenders.
Um, however, there is something very real about how we retain relationships and the ways in which we
can show up better. Um, better is not the right word. The ways in which we can show up more
holistically in order to retain our relationships. I can tell you that every relationship that I have
had with a black woman that has fallen off has been because when I shared with them, this thing that you
said, or this thing that you did affected me in this way, their response was to dismiss, to gaslight, um,
or to accuse. And, you know, in the process of working through my last relationship with my ex,
I had to do a lot of self-reflection on how I was showing up. Right. And I realized like,
Oh, I was doing that with him because my mom does that with me. However, I also then realized,
Oh, I am doing that with home girls as well. And so then I said, I need to shift how I respond.
I need to shift from defense to curiosity, right? From defense to curiosity. And the, the,
the benefit of this is that you can't lose. There's nothing that you lose in shifting from defense to
curiosity. It doesn't mean that you have now, um, it doesn't mean that you have now admitted to
something that you didn't do. It doesn't mean that you have quote unquote taken accountability for
something that you, that you, um, are being accused of it. But what it does is instead of closing doors,
it opens them. So I'll give you an example. I had a friend who, um, okay, I'll give you an example.
So when I moved, when I moved back to New York, I have, um, I have, I have three friends who were here
that I would have considered to be like my family. Right. And those three friends, I had been here
for five weeks and my moving truck was finally arriving. So my stuff was finally coming, but I
had been here for five weeks, like sleeping on the mattress, the air mattress, like all the things
going back and forth, trying to bring my cats, et cetera. And within those five weeks, none of them
said, can I come help? None of them said, how are you doing? None of them said, when can I, um,
at least come visit you. And this really hurt my feelings. Now, what I will say is there is a lot
of expectation more than I personally believe is should be expected. There's a lot of expectation
for people to deliver their hurt in a palatable way that somehow determines how you respond to
their hurt. And I would say that if you come from a place of curiosity, for the most part,
I don't think it really should matter unless they're trying to hurt you, which is its own thing,
but that's not what we're talking about here. So I sent them a text, all three of them are separate
texts, but they were all the same texts. And I said, I, um, I will use the Angela Rye situation in
this as an example after this, since I know y'all want to hear why I call her and Tiffany D cross mean
girls. And I have no shame about telling my version of that story. So I said, Hey y'all, I said, Hey,
Hey, um, and this is to the three friends. Hey, I've been here for six weeks. I haven't,
you haven't asked how I'm doing. You haven't asked if I need help and you haven't asked when you can
come see me. Is this how it's going to be now that I'm back in New York? So the first friend replied back
and said, I'm sorry that you're feeling alone. I just haven't had, you know, time or whatever,
whatever, to which I replied, but you have time for a man. Now I want to remind you all, I am 44.
So the people in my life are of a certain age. The next friend said, help question, mark,
question, mark, question, mark. I thought you paid somebody to help you. Um, I work two jobs
and don't have time to help you. Um, and then she went on to say, you know, that I was being
self-centered. Um, and for the record, her two jobs are, one of them is remote and one of them is,
is traveling. Um, so, so, you know, but this let me know like, Oh, none of them are white. These are all
black people. Um, and she was like, I did check on you. Um, but what I, but I, you know, their responses
were in no way acknowledging of the reality of the situation. My third friend, Brandon Victor Dixon
hit me and said, you know, I won't front. Like I felt away when I first read this text, but then I
realized you were sending the text because you felt unsupported. So when can I come visit and how can
I help? This is a really good example of, he needed a pause because his initial response was
defense, which is fair. However, then there was examination, right?
Right. And I think what happens so often is that we simply are unwilling to do the examination for fear
for fear. I, I've been in situations where I've had someone say to me, like, I didn't appreciate X, Y, Z
and I did the self-examination. I'm like, damn, I see you. And it's either that wasn't my intention.
However, I, I, I apologize for it landing that way or it's, you know, I, I had a blind spot there.
I missed, I missed the mark, you know, I missed the mark. I apologize. Um, so now I'm coming,
I'm coming back to it. And I think that we don't do enough of the curiosity as compassion practice.
We allow ourselves to, um, make these decisions about how we allow ourselves to let our emotions
emotions that are attached to trauma, make a decision about how we interact with people that
we claim to love. So have those friends been helpful in the past? Yes. But that was 10 years ago
before I lived here. And, um, I think that because I gained a certain level of monetary success,
they felt that I no longer needed their support. You know, who did come help me? Adrienne Bailon.
Adrienne Bailon came over and helped me put some candles away. So shout out to my good, my good buddy
aid. Um, the reason I consider Angela Rye and Tiffany D cross mean girls is because my feelings have never
been considered by them in response to their actions, even though I have expressed it to them.
And I consider anyone who behaves that way with people that they know to be mean girls. I think it's
really, um, just important to show people value by having curiosity and compassion around their feelings
and how you have treated them. And there's a particular way that atonement shows up that is not
passive. Atonement is assertive. It is, um, assertive is not the word word. Atonement is, um,
purposeful. Atonement is, um, direct. It's not something that you're trying to, that someone has
to figure out intentional. It is humble. You know, like that's the part that so many of us always have
to work on is the, the humble part, right? Because you, you, it's like, you still want to not be seen
as the bad person. And the truth of the matter is that just because you may have not shown up in your
best self doesn't mean you were a bad person. It can be reflective of a bad moment and you can
completely shift the energy of that. You can balance that karma out. Um, I was a member of a group chat
that had both of them in it. And then I realized that I was no longer in the group chat after they
went on a trip. And, um, and I was like, oh, you know, I, I, I guess I accidentally left the group
chat only to learn that I had been removed from the group chat because apparently I was not engaging
enough. And for what it's worth, um, if someone is not engaging enough, I feel like there's a fair
respect to simply reach out to them on the side and ask, are you okay? Um, and I think it's really
necessary for us in, in protecting our friendships, protecting our relationships in giving them the,
um, giving them the worthiness that they deserve. We have to extend ourselves sometimes in ways that are
uncomfortable. However, it's just the thing that you do, right? So if, if I am removed from a group
chat with women that I revere and no one felt compelled to say to me, Hey, do you still want to
be in this group chat? Cause it looks like you're not conversing. Um, I look at that as funny style.
Now I had taken myself out of the group chat months before, because at the time I was pregnant and I was
not clear headed and there was a lot of talk about politics that was like frustrating me. And so I
removed myself from the group chat. However, I was later added back by Tiffany. So, um, you know,
it was quite a shock to me to hear, Oh, we, I removed you because you weren't interacting and this
is, and the space is a personal space. And I re I respect that.
I respect that. I also know that when you have regard for somebody, you also understand how they
would respond to that, right? Like removing somebody from a space without their knowledge
is simply mean. And it says that you are discarding them. It says that you do not value them.
And when they address, Hey, that was shitty. And your response is, I'm sorry, you feel that way.
Something to that effect, but please let us know if you will, if you need any support,
that's disingenuous. So then when I see Tiffany a couple months later and it comes up and then I say,
you know, that I'm, I'm really, that really was not cool. And the response is, wow, you still seem
bothered by it. You know, Amanda, we're all very busy and we simply just don't have the time.
And you're right. Removing myself may have looked like that for them as well.
However, that was clarified later. And the difference is always in communication. That's
the difference because you have every right to communicate. If you feel like someone was sideways,
when you do not do that, you are leaving many things open for assumption and for trauma-based
responses. And so communication helps to, to allow what communication allows us to not, um, dip into
those spaces. Like y'all know what it's like. If, if, if someone said they don't text you and they don't text
you, you start filling in the blanks, but you fill in the blanks with your own bullshit. So you want
to come up? So I think it's, it's also sometimes people simply not wanting to acknowledge the ways
in which they are harming folks. And I am not quiet about the way I've been harmed. So no one is in
mystery. No one is confused about if I was sad, if I was bothered, if I had my feelings hurt, nobody.
So there's no excuse. And this is what so many of us do in our friend circles. We don't tell people
how we feel. We carry resentment. Um, we don't tell people how we feel and, and then we retaliate.
Hey, we don't tell people how we feel and we project. All of us are guilty. We do it all the time.
We do it all the time. And it is, it is not emotionally mature. So at a certain point we have to then
say, okay, well, this isn't a result. Like I can't blame lack of maturity now. I mean,
I can't blame youth anymore. This is just lack of maturity. So who am I blocking? Oh, this person who
somehow seems to know about my life in a way that I love it. I love it. I think what's interesting is
that sometimes people will try to align how I interact with strangers on an internet with how I
interact with actual real people. It's not the same. I don't even know who's a bot, who not,
who's an op, who not. So a lot of times when I see that type of response, that's someone saying,
you do that to us and we don't do that. You know, it's like, like someone here just said,
we are real people, Amanda. Who, how do you know that? That's not actually factual. There are bots
everywhere. But here's the other part of it. I reserve the right to call people mean girls that
I feel are mean girls. And the truth of the matter is there just is not the same outrage for when I am
called all type of shit. There is no curiosity. There is no, um, you know, effort to get to the
bottom of it. It becomes simply just, we're running with this. And I see that I've been, I've lived in
this body and the trend is exponential. There is not an, there is no investigative curiosity. And, um,
it doesn't matter, you know, how much we, if we want to stay in defense mode in our real friendships,
as well as in our digital spaces, we're just not going to get anywhere. That's why on such a regular
basis, I have to be like, let me not, let me not, like, be defensive about this. Let me be proactive.
Let me be exploratory about it. Right? Let me be, um, investigative. Let me be curious.
And for me, that's been a very helpful way to move through, um, the world because it's also allowed
me to identify relationships that are better suited for me. I need to be in relationships and closeness
with people who see my feelings as valuable and who are not afraid to, um, address them head on.
Right? And so that requires people who are doing that work for themselves. Like I can't be in a
relationship with a man on a romantic level or, you know, friends on any level, uh, who can't
have whole, who don't hold space for vulnerability. I had a conversation the other day. I had a friend
here and, um, she was talking, but she just kept talking kind of like to herself, even though I was
here. Um, and eventually I said, you know, you're talking, but you're not talking to me. And she was
like, well, what do you mean? Like, I'll just be quiet. I'm talking too much. And I was like, no,
no, it's not that you're talking too much. However, it's just that you're not talking to me. Like, I
feel like you're kind of like ranting and I'm present, but I want to be engaged. And in that,
in that context, in that moment, it could have been, well, she could have taken that all the way to
the left, but she was like, huh? And immediately shifted. And we had such a more, um, fruitful time
together because we were in conversation. You know, this is what I try to do. Um, I mean, I'm not, I don't
want to compare this, but like, I don't like when I watch interviews where I'm like watching the person
wait for the person to stop talking to then just respond. Like let's be in exchange. I want to listen
to what you have to say. Right. And I thought that was a really dope moment. Um, because,
and it was really honestly, very, um, encouraging for me because I feel like I get misinterpreted
so often when I bring to somebody like, Hey, this thing that you said did not sit well with me.
Um, I said that to somebody the other day. I said, you know, at one point in time, you talked
about this person and it did not sit well with me, how you addressed me. And I accommodated you
in the moment, you know, just in order to diffuse things, but it still resonates with me. And they
were very offended by me saying that because the thing about it is that we have been trained
to feel like we are not allowed or it's, it's, um, we've been trained to feel like if you simply
share with somebody that they have bothered your regulation, that you're like scolding them
when that's not always the case. I mean, scolding comes off a certain way. Um, scolding is a very
different thing, but when you say this resonates with me, that's why they have that therapy language.
I don't know, Malika Hustle. I don't know what your deal is, but you're, you're getting blocked.
It's not the delivery to be quite honest. I think at this point, you know, folks just receive shit in
whatever voice they hear. But one of the things that a lot of us will not admit is that we have
been raised in a narcissist country. The culture of the United States is narcissistic. This is a nation
that has taught us through years of indoctrination since we were children, that it is impervious to
critique, that it is the best and out may outweighing and out measuring anything and anywhere else
that anything or anyone challenging this country is doing so because they want to harm it.
So we have grown up in this environment and there's no way of really avoiding that unless you have
folks around you who are actively doing like counter-mindfulness and or you yourself are
counter-mindfulness, are practicing counter-mindfulness. And yes, Casey Cass Dillon,
narcissists are revered and exalted. However, there's also just narcissism.
Sometimes you just have a narcissistic response. Sometimes you have, you're not necessarily a
narcissist, but you have narcissism. You have ways in which your narcissism exists. So, you know,
that is something to like, you know, be present with. I think there's a narcissistic response that many
of us default to when we are addressed directly about our behavior. And that narcissistic response
is to protect our feelings. So, the shift in that becomes, this isn't about my feelings.
This is about their feelings. And in this moment, they're expressing their feelings.
And I can hold space for that. So, there's work we got to do. So, Eric, what's Eric's last name?
Um, hold on. So, Eric Morrison-Smith was in the chat earlier. And, um, he is the, uh, founder and the head of
the, um, Alliance for, um, Boys and Men of Color. And when he was on Views for Amanda Land,
he talked about how in doing coalition work with all these different organizations,
excuse me, all these different organizations, one of the things that ends up being a, an impediment
is the fact that there's so much trauma in the space that, you know, people can't get past the
trauma to get to the work. So, before we can even get to the coalition building, we have to get through
the trauma. And so, that is what I am trying to just throw out to consider for you guys tonight.
Because it is 1,000% a time of extremism. The gaslighting is at an all-time high.
And the lack of empathy is deeply disturbing. So, we have to combat these efforts, these practices,
internally, molecularly, on a cellular level. Do you understand what I'm saying? That requires
attention that only you can pay to yourself. It requires rigor and intention that only you can
apply. So, I encourage you to challenge yourself to lead with curiosity versus defense in any situation
situation with people that you value. Now, I ain't gonna lie to you. Sometimes it's like, man, go fuck
yourself. I ain't gonna lie to you. But, you know, like I started teaching an art class to kids. And,
you know, children are extremely open a lot of times, unless they've suffered very severe trauma.
They are very open and willing to kind of just be their full selves.
So, it was like 10 kids. I had them all give me a high five. And then, this one kid was like,
I'm not giving you a high five. I said, oh, why not? Because I don't feel like it. So, all right.
Well, think about it. You know, we'll come back around to it. So, later in the class,
I said, well, first of all, these fifth graders was talking about NATO and Korea and all type of
things. And then I heard them talking about, well, what if England tries to take revenge?
And I said, why would England try to take revenge? And one of them said, well, because,
you know, we beat them in the Revolutionary War. And so, then the other young lady who was
not giving me my high five, she said, well, also, there's a War of 1812.
I said, so, what was the War of 1812? And she said, a war that happened in 1812.
And I said, don't get smart with me. I let you slide the first time, but there's not going to be
another time. What is the War of 1812? And she looked at me and I looked at her and she looked
at me and she said, the War of 1812 was a war. Like, let's not get gassed. Okay. I let you live.
And so, then the counselor after was like, you know, I was going to check her. But then I saw you
had it handled. So, I said, you know what? I said, I'm just, I'm a, oh, man. And then I asked them
because they were talking about taking over the world. And I asked them, so, what happens when you
take over the world? And they said, you own the world. And I said, well, what happens when you own
the world? You own all the land. I said, so, what happens when you own all the land? Well, then you
can, like, you know, determine how people live. And I said, okay. So, what's the plan?
Um, in terms of, like, how they would live. And one of them said, well, I mean, I wouldn't
make anyone my slave. Got it. Cool, cool, cool. That's good. Um, and so, I let them sit with
that. And then I said to them, well, here's a question for you. What was the world before
it was owned? Who, who, who, who, who's, whose was the world before there were countries?
And, uh, high five said, it was natives, natives. And I said, would you like to know a word
that is a more positive word for that? She said, yes. And I said, indigenous. And she went
indigenous. And then the counselor across the room went, indigenous. The exercise that
I did with the children today is reflective of essentially what I'm talking to you guys
about. And what I, in, in, in that it was, it was an exercise around being in community.
They each had a piece of paper. They had all these art supplies and they could do whatever
they want with the art supplies. And then I would say, switch. And they had to find another,
um, then they had to go to another piece of paper and, um, sorry, someone just asked me
a question on here. And so then they had to go, they had to go to someone else's and add
to that. And then they did it one more time. So by the end of the class, all of the artwork
had been touched by each of them. And when they looked at the artwork, they were able to
see, oh, I did that. And that one, oh, I did that. And that one, oh, I did that. And that
one. And it was really cool to see them, um, be able to see themselves in all these different
spaces. And I said to them, you know, this is what community is. You're showing up differently
in these different spaces, but it's all the same space. Hold on. Let me block this jackass.
So next week we're going to do something around nature. I got all these different little mini
animals. And then I asked them to think about like, what are, what is their like favorite
parts of nature? And so they're going to be combining the animals and their favorite parts
of nature, whether they match or not. It might be a tiger in the ocean. You know, it might
be, um, it might be, uh, a Tyrannosaurus Rex in daisies, but, um, I want them to, you know,
be thinking about nature. I don't know what high five gonna do. I don't know. Um, oh, that's
what's up Nola. So I will leave you all with, again, this exercise around interacting with
each other. Um, to be quite honest, Nadia, I, I think I have, I am maternal, but I don't have the
energy capacity to be a parent. Like, I feel like I would have suffered autism burnout like every other
day if I were a parent, to be quite honest. Um, I actually had a psychic tell me, she was like,
do you want kids? And I was like, no. And she was like, oh, good. And I was like, why? And she was
like, because the way your chart is set up, um, kids would fuck you up mentally. Congratulations,
Nadia. She was like, the way your thing is laid out, like it would really mess you up. So, um,
but I'm here for the, I'm here as auntie though. I got a couple of little nieces and nephews floating
around here. Okay. But my, I, I was never designed to be a parent because I'm for the world
and I, and not being the parent of a child has allowed me a certain level of, of, uh, freedom
and carelessness that is needed to stand the way I do. So I, the word of the day is curiosity.
Emotional maturity is not about, in my opinion, emotional maturity is not about, um, it's not
necessarily about the books you've read, but it's a bit, it's, it's about being willing to read
yourself. As for Bad Bunny at the Superbowl, I can't feel conflicted about that. Bad Bunny is a like
major, huge star. Like, why wouldn't he do the Superbowl? Now I'll tell you this,
there better not be one word of English in that show. And I better be able to smell the rice and
beans through the goddamn screen. Okay. Not somebody I'm here using porno terms. I had to
take it down, Wendigard, because people were like, oh, you're not speaking real Spanish. But I will tell
you. I'm about to listen to Violet Omidabla right now.
Jamming.
It is definitely time to go to bed. Bunny songs, but I know a good amount of Spanish.
Anyways, again, again, curiosity. I will say this, one of the best, one of the things that was most
helpful for me that I continue to have to implement is seeing myself as a being,
seeing myself as an energy space, an energy field that exists in a world of other energy fields and
energy spaces. And in looking at myself kind of like a, if you're like a, like, if you look at like
a Venn diagram, sometimes you and someone else's energy space are going to have to overlap. Doesn't
mean that boundary isn't still there, but it overlaps. And in that overlap
overlap is where you are able to find out what the dealio is without giving your whole self over to
it. You're just giving this much. You're just giving this much to the, to the conversation,
to the space, to the situation. And if we're not willing to give that much,
we're not going to get anything. We're not going to get anything from each other and we're not going
to get anywhere. So particularly around people that you claim to revere, particularly around people
that you claim to love, to protect, there needs to be a shared willingness to do that.
And I've said this before, one of the easiest ways to find that out is to share with somebody
vulnerability. And how they respond to that vulnerability gives you a great indication
on whether or not it gets, it's a great indication on how far your Venn diagrams can overlap.
Good night. Make sure to go support my work at amandalandexports.com. Make sure to watch
Views from Amanda Land on Wednesday morning, 10 a.m. Eastern. Tomorrow morning, I'll be doing two
Instagram lives with members on the Freedom Flotilla, on the Global Summit Flotilla.
They are approaching Gessa tomorrow. They are expecting to be boarded and incarcerated at around,
I guess it would be, they're seven hours ahead. So 5, 4, 3, 2, 1, 12, 11, 10 a.m.
So at roughly 11 a.m. Eastern time. So tonight, I would like for you to lift them up in whatever
exchange that you do with the energy space. Pray, meditate, jumping jacks, whatever. And do the same
with the people of Gessa, of Sudan, of the Congo, of Chicago, of Portland, of everywhere. Okay?